# **KEITH LI**

#### PASSIONATE FRONT END DEVELOPER

(343) 988-3668 | <u>keithli9395@gmail.com</u> | <u>https://www.iamkeithli.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/keithli93</u> | <u>https://github.com/hereiskeith</u>

## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Extreme passionate Front End Developer with experience of front end web development and building user interfaces and UX using React from the ground up – design, development, unit testing, delivery and maintenance. Proficient in an assortment of web development technologies and tools.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Front End Developer

April 2020 - Present

https://eleduck.com/maskhero & https://github.com/eleduck/maskhero

- Main contributor to the open-source project: a Covid-19 event to help people all across the world
- Built through React and has raised 3700 masks & over 10,000 Chinese Yuan and assisted 260 families
- Optimized Jest and Babel configurations with Webpack and performed unit-tests for components
- Followed Git & Github workflow to collaborate with other contributors

Web Developer April 2020 – Present

OcuXcel, Ottawa, Canada

Tech Stack: Angular, TypeScript, RxJS, Angular Material, Firebase, AngularFire, Nx CLI

- Volunteer of a humanitarian project to enhance the capability of telehealth during Covid-19 closure of medical clinics, cancellation of regular appointments and check-ups
- Developing a web app to enable certain patients to perform self-tests and connect with their doctors
- Implementing AngularFire to authenticate users and store related data in NoSQL Firebase cloud store
- Following Agile development and using Agile development methodologies through the development cycle

#### Junior Front End Developer / Research Assistant

May 2019 - April 2020

University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada

Project: E-commerce Mobile Hybrid App Development for Local Merchants (BizMSM Github Link)

Tech Stack: React, Material-UI, Apache Cordova, PhoneGap, styled components, Redux, REST API, Axios

- Designed and built two sets of user interface for consumers and merchants and managed state via Redux
- Integrated with PayPal checkout API and Google Map API to allow top-up and accurate location service
- Verified and authenticated transactions and records with Block-chain technologies
- Packaged and supported the deployment of releases on the Android platform

Project: Bitcoin Trend Dashboard App (Dashboard Github Link)

Tech Stack: React, SASS, Redux, CSS Grid, CSS Flexbox, Highcharts, react-highcharts, Heroku

- Created a pixel-perfect match and fully-responsive website with great user experiences from the design
- Styled and developed reusable functional UI components without the help of any CSS and UI frameworks.
- Facilitated data displaying fetched from open API using Highcharts & react-highcharts
- Deployed and built the website on the cloud through Heroku

D.L. Engineering Inc., Richmond Hill, Canada

- Coordinated with clients on-site and through phone and email
- Designed wood structural buildings with computer-aid software including AutoCAD and Woodworks

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript ES6, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, CSS preprocessors (SASS), SQL

Library/Framework: React, Redux, Angular, RxJS, Node.js, express, Jest, Material-UI, Bootstrap

Database management Systems: MongoDB, MySQL

Web services: REST API, JSON, AJAX, Axios

Technologies/Tools: Firebase, Netlify, Heroku, Husky, Apache Cordova, GIT, Github, NPM, Webpack

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES**

Node with React: Full-stack Web Development Certification

March 2020

Udemy, E-learning

Master of Engineering, GPA 9.7/10

Sep 2016 - June 2018

University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada

Bachelor of Engineering, GPA 8.6/10

Sep 2012 – June 2016

Guangdong University of Technology, Guangzhou, China